The legend has arrived
The Monkey King is a animation, fantasy, adventure
film directed by Anthony Stacchi.
A stick-wielding monkey teams with a young girl on an epic quest for immortality,
battling demons, dragons, gods — and his own ego — along the way.
Monkey King (voice), played by Jimmy O. Yang.
Dragon King (voice), played by Bowen Yang.
Lin (voice), played by Jolie Hoang-Rappaport.
Benbo (voice), played by Jo Koy.
Babbo (voice), played by Ron Yuan.
Stick (voice), played by Nan Li.
The Monkey King is a 2023 animated fantasy action comedy film directed by Anthony Stacchi from a
screenplay written by Rita Hsiao and the writing team of Steve Bencich and Ron J.
It is based on the first 7 chapters of the classic
Ming dynasty novel, Journey to the West.
The film stars Jimmy O.
Yang as the voice of the titular trickster, with Bowen Yang, Jo Koy, BD Wong,
Jolie Hoang-Rappaport, and Stephanie Hsu in supporting roles.
The Monkey King was selected as the closing film at the 22nd New York Asian Film Festival, where it had its
world premiere on July 30, 2023, and was distributed and released on August 18, 2023, by Netflix.
On December 7, it appeared in the eligible list for consideration of Academy Award for Best
Animated Feature for the 96th Academy Awards, but ultimately did not appear.
The tone is lighthearted.